EMMA JUDGE

Chicago, IL 60614 | cell: 847-361-5528 emmalyn.judge@icloud.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and creative research administration professional, committed to the pursuit of knowledge and helping others. Tactful, conscientious individual experienced in creating and maintaining relationships within an organization and with external collaborators to maximize efficiency, build valuable connections, and ensure the successful completion of projects. Extensive practice in balancing discrete tasks with broader objectives enables this self-motivated problem solver to successfully manage a diverse and demanding portfolio without compromising output or quality.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY | Chicago, IL

September 2018 - Present

Senior Research Administrator - Department of Psychiatry & Behavioral Sciences

- Existing responsibilities, as Research Administrator (below), were expanded such that workload increased in size, complexity, and variety of assignments. New responsibilities with a focus on team leadership were added
- Serves as a team leader and individual mentor for colleagues. This role has provided valuable insight about how to develop successful teams and delegate effectively, to ensure optimal group and individual outcomes
- Collaborates with department to ensure that the needs of my division and constituents are adequately represented, providing strategies that address specific concerns without compromising broader aims

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY | Chicago, IL

June 2016 - September 2018

Research Administrator - Department of Psychiatry & Behavioral Sciences

- Existing responsibilities, as Associate Research Administrator (below), were expanded such that workload increased in size, complexity, scope and variety of assignments
- Acts as liaison between department and institutional offices such as OSR, ASRSP, IACUC, IRB, NUCOI and
 payroll, funding and regulatory agencies, university institutes and recharge centers, external contractors and
 consultants. Additionally, facilitates communication among various departmental constituents
- Helps develop and implement strategic plans regarding grants and contracts by providing suggestions gleaned through attending internal & external meetings, interpreting clauses, reviewing contracts, and identifying/ resolving common issues. Offers input and recommendations to increase productivity & effectiveness

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY | Chicago, IL

June 2015 - June 2016

Associate Research Administrator - Department of Psychiatry & Behavioral Sciences

- Performs lifecycle administration of federal grants, foundation awards, clinical trials & industry sponsored research from proposal development and submission to post-award management and closeout
- Responsible for reviewing and reconciling grant expenditures on a monthly basis and, more broadly, monitoring financial activity to ensure that all costs are reasonable, allocable, allowable and consistent
- Routinely reviews pertinent policies to ensure compliance with federal uniform guidance, contract terms, sponsor-specific rules and regulations, as well as university policy regarding COI, expense allowability, effort reporting, etc. Familiarity with the aforementioned guidelines further enables me to monitor the completion of deliverables and adherence to a project's approved aims, timeline and budget

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY | Chicago, IL

October 2014 - June 2015

Program Assistant - Department of Psychiatry & Behavioral Sciences

- Facilitated the daily activities of a lab group with both basic and clinical operations by prioritizing current tasks, tending to unforeseen situations and providing general support to all group members
- Helped manage 15+ sponsored and non-sponsored accounts, including clinical trials, foundation grants and charitable donations, using Cognos reports, InfoEd and NUFinancials. Also created and maintained Excel sheets to track balances, forecast spending and project future budgets – always taking personal responsibility of tasks to ensure they were completed with a high degree of accuracy
- Developed mastery for managing multiple projects while remaining mindful of each one's individual components by remaining engaged in daily operations and thoroughly addressing all details

JUDICIAL HOLDINGS LLC | Chicago, IL

July 2013 - October 2014

Executive Assistant & Administrative Manager

Family investment partnership. Holdings include a software company prosecuting a patent infringement case, a solar panel rental company, and a landfill recycling, composting and green electricity project.

- Provided administrative services including creating daily agendas, scheduling conference calls, coordinating travel, answering phones, and ensuring all files are organized and updated as needed
- Performed research and due diligence in regard to potential projects. Aided CEO in assessment and evaluation of investments by summarizing research findings

THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS | Austin, TX Lab Coordinator & Research Assistant

May 2012 - July 2013

The Twin Project Lab is dedicated to the on-going study of child and teenage twins in Austin and central Texas. The project's goal is to investigate the variance within twin pairs by collecting and examining measures of behavioral, social, emotional, and intellectual data. http://sites.la.utexas.edu/twinproject/

- Maintained lab organization and functionality by organizing physical and electronic files, performing upkeep of participant database (REDCap & Excel), creating payment receipts, and following up with participants post test
- Contacted potential participants, answered questions, provided guidance, coordinated schedules, and sustained relationships with participants via telephone, in person, or written correspondence
- Through collaboration with faculty, I garnered a comprehensive understanding of how to develop a lean team that is able to function in the most effective manner within the framework of academia and budget constraints
- · Gained experience working with confidential data and coding files to maintain anonymity
- · Attained further insight into academic publishing, journal and grant writing, and peer review

INTERNSHIPS

ABARIS CAPITAL ADVISORS LLC. | Chicago, IL Executive Assistant & Analyst

May 2010 - August 2010

A boutique investment management firm \$2BB AUA specializing in asset management, portfolio structuring, and advice for sovereign wealth funds, global financial institutions, international private banking operations and family offices representing ultra-high net worth individuals.

- Primary assistant to company President and COO. Provided support to executives and synchronized all constituents. Prepared presentation materials, arranged meeting times and managed venues
- Coordinated all travel international and otherwise, managed daily agendas and long-term projects
- Functioned as admin supervisor to ensure continuity and procurement of goods and accounting thereof
- · Scheduled meetings, travel plans, and daily agendas. Coordinated and organized files

EDUCATION

The University of Texas, Austin, Texas — Bachelor of Arts, Psychology, Minor in French; May 2013

· Awards: Dean's Honor List - Cum Laude

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS & MEMBERSHIPS:

Organization	Dates
National Council of University Research Administrators (NCURA)	12/2015 to present
Northwestern University Research Administration Professionals (NURAP)	06/2015 to present
Association of Clinical Research Professionals (ACRP)	06/2018 to present

VOLUNTEER WORK & OTHER EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

Name of Company	Title	Dates
C.A.R.E. of South Bend	Volunteer	10/2013 to 10/2017
Childcare Services	Nanny	2006 to 2014 (seasonal / sporadically)
Starbucks	Barista	11/2010 to 07/2013
Autism Speaks	Fundraiser	11/2009 to 11/2011